I was so very happy
when you smiled at me,
A smile that melted everything away.
Spring is still far away,
and within the cold ground,
I awaited the time when
sprouts would put forth their buds.
Even supposing today there
may have been some pain,
And though the scars of yesterday remain,
You can go on living as much
as your heart wants to believe.
You cannot be born again, although
You can go on changing yourself, and so
Let's stay together, always.
It has cleared up completely!
Okay then, Mother, please
watch over things today, too.
I'm off!
Pleased to meet you. I'm Honda Tohru.
In May of this year, my mother,
who had been raising me all alone,
was killed in a traffic accident.
As a result, I am now
secretly living in a tent.
I can't say that it's an
easy life, but that's okay.
One of my virtues is that no matter
the times, I will not be discouraged.
Huh?
Mother, I've discovered something!
There is a house standing here.
It's has such a relaxed feel to it.
How cute!
Twelve ornaments, from the zodiac.
Huh?
How can it be that there is a girl here?
P- pardon me!
I looked without asking first!
Go ahead, go ahead. I'm just
drying them in the sun, after all.
However, they couldn't
be that interesting
for such a young person to look at.
Not at all. They are very cute.
Really? In that case,
I'm happy. I like them too.
Still, just as I thought,
there is no cat, huh?
Cat? Ah...
Could it be you're referring to the cat
that appears in the tales of the zodiac?
Yes.
My mother told them to me quite often.
A long time ago,
God told the animals,
"I invite you to come to the
banquet that I shall hold tomorrow.
Make sure not to be late."
When he heard that, the rat,
who liked to play pranks,
Yes, sir,
yes, sir.
Is that clear?
When he heard that, the rat,
who liked to play pranks,
Yes, sir,
yes, sir.
Is that clear?
lied to the cat who lived near him,
Ho, thank you.
Yes, sir,
yes, sir.
Is that clear?
lied to the cat who lived near him,
Ho, thank you.
Yes, sir,
yes, sir.
Is that clear?
saying that the banquet
was the day after next.
The next day, the rat rode upon the
ox's back before the banquet hall,
Welcome to
the Banquet
where he lightly jumped down.
Welcome to
the Banquet
After him came the ox,
the tiger, and so on.
Welcome to
the Banquet
The banquet was delightful,
and went on until morning.
Only the cat, who had been
tricked, was left out.
What are you crying about, Tohru?
I feel so sorry for him!
I feel so sorry for cat-san!
I've made up my mind! I'm giving up
Dog-san, and I will become Cat-san!
Oh, yeah? I wonder what kind of
face he'll make when he hears that.
"He?"
So, you're the year of the Dog, then?
I'm feeling a sense of affinity.
You see, I, too am a Dog--
What are you flirting around here for?
Are you okay, Honda-san? My cousin
didn't do anything impolite, did he?
S- Sohma-kun!
Mother, it doesn't seem real!
It's Sohma-kun!
The prince of my school, Sohma Yuki,
is standing before my eyes!
--That's quite a heavy bag you've got.
--Then this is Sohma Yuki-kun's house.
You have a dictionary
or something in there?
Yeah, two of them.
Oh? So you're Yuki-kun's classmate, then?
Then, from the top-- I am Sohma
Shigure, Yuki-kun's cousin.
Honda Tohru.
Honda-san, what brings you to this area?
My house is, um, near.
Near? To here?
Y- yes...
W- well, with that, I should be--
Ah, Honda-san...
Yes?
Since you're already here,
shall we go together?
L - O - V- E, Lovely Yuki!
Honda-san!
What on earth was that about!?
Would you like to explain to us clearly
how you came to school
together with Sohma-kun?
I- It was an accident.
If you could get away with accidents,
we wouldn't need the police!
When it comes to Sohma-kun,
of 1st Year, Section D,
at Kaiwara High School,
there isn't a girl student around
who doesn't know how
he is so attractive--
--and clearheaded--
--both scholarly and athletic!
And yet he will not deign to let us, the
"Prince Yuki" fan club, come near him!
--Hey!
--What!?
Tohru said it was by accident, didn't she?
Don't go attaching any idiotic
pretexts to it, you hear?
Why, you!
You Yankees think that if you threaten
enough, you can get away with anything!
I will make you ------ with harmful vibes.
Uo-chan, Hana-chan, you saved me!
That was a disaster,
huh Tohru? There, there...
Hanajima, don't
seriously send out any vibes.
Cooking Room
Sohma-kun is overly attractive,
and just looking at him standing
next to me made me nervous.
I couldn't make any conversation with
him worth calling conversation, either.
I sense an unusual vibe from him...
Here it comes-- Hanajima's Vibe Report.
Unusual, you say?
I'm not quite sure about it.
Well, there certainly is an
unusual feeling about him.
I hear he doesn't talk much about himself.
Earlier, there was this 2nd-year girl...
...who after declaring herself,
tried to embrace him.
He thrust her away as hard as he
could, and looked terrified himself.
Odd for a student to do these days.
T- thank you very much.
Tohru, do you have work today?
Yes, I do.
That's rough. You're still staying with
your grandpa on your dad's side, right?
Y- yes...
You promised you'd pay your
own tuition, didn't you?
Y- yes.
Still,
since this is a prefecture-run school,
I wouldn't think you would have to
work so much just to cover tuition.
W- well, it's...
You're getting him to
feed you decent, right?
You're not getting swindled out of
everything from your paycheck, right?
R- right...
Really? Fine, then. If anything like
that happens, tell me right away.
I'll see that they don't get away with it.
O- okay.
I couldn't tell them.
I couldn't tell Uo-chan and
Hana-chan that I was living in a tent.
--Tohru, Mama sure would
like some Sukiyaki today.
--My mother, who worked and worked
after my father passed away
Family Budget
in order to support us...
--Hooray! Meat, meat!
--My mother, who was always
so powerful and cheerful...
I never would have thought
she would die in an accident.
There was some amount of squabbling
over who would take care of me...
But in the end, it was decided I would
go to the house of my grandfather,
on my father's side.
I promised to pay my own tuition, so
as not to be a burden to my grandfather,
who was living on a pension.
That was in May.
Four months later...
However, Grandfather
came to live together
with his daughter and her husband,
and as it happened, their
house needed remodeling.
I was asked if I could stay with one of
my friends or something during that time.
Uo-chan lives in a one-room apartment,
and there are five people
in Hana-chan's family.
I couldn't very well make
trouble for them. However...
I've got it!
I was going to live by
myself at some point
myself at some point.
This will be a good chance!
Sohma-kun, about this
morning, I beg your pardon.
The same goes even more for me.
Shigure must have given you trouble.
No, he is a very fine person. He let
me see his ornaments of the zodiac.
You said something about being of
the year of the Cat, didn't you?
I was a bit off-kilter as a child.
Cats are fools. They have a bad nature.
Honda-san, did you know...
...that the zodiac is really part of a
timekeeping system of tens and twelves?
N- no...
Originally, they were used
as numerals, or as timepieces.
Afterward, they got adopted into
Yin-yang cosmology and divination,
and they were used in fortune-telling.
Did the animals have
anything to do with it?
Mm-mm. Apparently, it's not clearly known
at what time animals were adapted in,
or what source they
were established from,
but since the beginning,
there was never a time when the
Cat was a member of the zodiac.
Still, since it has come to
be associated with the zodiac,
whatever they say goes.
Cats really are fools, you know.
So, in short, Sohma-kun, do you hate cats?
I was thinking this morning, as well,
that your color doesn't look too good.
You should take better care of yourself.
Well, see you tomorrow.
He really is mysterious.
Even so, Sohma-kun, I'll
pretend I didn't hear that.
I'm sure Mother had it much, much harder!
Ladies, hurry and take
care of this garbage here!
Okay!
I can't get discouraged!"Never give up!"
I'm getting tired of eating
out every day like this.
Well, Shigure, cook something.
When I cook, you complain, don't you?
If there are pickled radishes in my curry,
you bet I want to complain a little.
Yuki-kun, you're a smart one,
but you're completely hopeless when
it comes to housework in general.
Say, how about we hire a housekeeper?
A woman would be trouble.
Huh?
Honda-san...
I'm home, mother.
I'm sleepy, but I still have
to do these printouts today.
I'll go wash my face in
the water of the stream.
Shigure, you're laughing too much.
I see. So that's why
you're living in a tent.
Yes...
Since when?
Since one week ago.
I thought it was strange.
This whole area is Sohma land, and
none of it has been leased or sold.
Um, if you would, please let
me borrow that spot temporarily.
Once the remodeling is complete,
I will leave immediately.
I don't have much money,
but I will pay you.
Please.
It's dangerous over there.
The dirt in those cliffs is loose,
and every once in a while,
molesters may come around.
And it's unreasonable to have
a girl spend so many months
living in a tent in
the first place, isn't it?
Are you finished laughing?
Mm-hm.
It's all right!
I've gotten used to the slugs,
and I have plenty of stamina and drive...
Honda-san!
She has a fever.
Let's see... Ice, ice!
I- it's the Sea of Corruption...
That's a good analogy!
There. Just now, it appears
there was a landslide somewhere.
U- um, how can you tell?
Something of an intuition
of the wild, I suppose.
Is it nearby?
Close to the tent... or maybe not!
This is terrible! Mother was...
There was a picture of
Mother inside the tent!
Mother!
Honda-san, calm down. You have a fever.
But, Mother is...
What should I do? If I don't get her out
of there quickly, Mother will suffer...
Once it gets brighter,
we'll come here again.
If a second calamity was
to occur and you got hurt,
it would hurt your mother even more.
Okay?
Yuki-kun is looking for some ice now.
You'll have to excuse me.
It's probably exhaustion.
The strain on you could be piling up.
I've lost my home again...
Is that hard on you?
No...
I know something that's even harder...
What's that?
I didn't say... "Come back soon."
The morning of the day
Mother died in the accident.
I had a short test... so I studied into
the morning... and then couldn't get up.
It was only that morning that I didn't
say it... even though I always said it...
It was only that morning...
I... didn't want to go to high school...
I thought instead I would work...
However, Mother said...
I only graduated from
middle school myself.
But I still would have liked to see
what being a high school
girl is like, you know?
That's why you're going to enjoy
the high school life in my place.
I understood... that all that
time, she was working for me...
And yet, I couldn't say
"Come back soon" to Mother.
I wasn't even able to see
her back as she left to work.
And so, I want to at least...
I want to safely graduate from high
school, which Mother wanted me to attend.
That is my... goal...
This is... no time...
to be outdone by... a fever...
Terrific, huh?
At school, she always seems so cheerful.
It seemed like she had never known
hardship or anything of the sort.
I had planned on running
away from the House of Sohma...
but in the end, here I am,
still among the Sohma...
If I really didn't like it,
I could have done like Honda-san,
and carried away a tent,
and gone off to either
somewhere unexplored,
or to the back country, or someplace.
I've had it easy, huh?
It would be rude to
Tohru-kun to call it terrific.
You're right.
Can I leave her up to you?
I'm going to go out.
Where to?
Don't tell me you're going to go dig
that stuff out. Should I go with you?
It'll be tough all alone, right?
Alone?
Who do you think you're talking to?
Come back soon.
Tohru...
Tohru?
You've gotten a fever again.
There's no need for you to
overdo it helping with the housework.
Tohru, you can just be yourself,
and take things slowly.
You'll overtake them sometime.
But...
Tohru, be yourself...
Mother...
How come...
Morning!
How are you feeling?
I think I was able to dig out all of
your belongings. Could you check them?
Sohma-kun, did you go through
all that dirt by yourself?
Don't be silly!
Then, how did you...?
It's a secret.
It's a dirty house, and all...
...and there are only guys here,
but right there on the second floor,
there is one room available.
Until the remodeling is finished,
you can stay in this house.
T- that won't do! I must object to that!
The room does have a lock on it.
That's not what I meant!
How shall I say this...?
Tohru-kun, do you like housework?
For example, cleaning,
and cooking, and so on?
Um... yes, I do like that.
Welcome to the House of Sohma!
I'll carry your things up too.
Ah, Yuki-kun, let her
borrow a change of clothes.
Y- you can't! Not only did you tend
to me, you're giving me a room now?
I'm putting you to too much trouble!
Honda-san, we're suggesting
this because we want to,
so don't think you're being any
trouble, and take us up on it.
Besides, you have
nowhere else to go, right?
Right...
Um, in that case, if
I'm going to put you out,
then please tell me
about whatever rules
and customs the House of
Sohma has, and everything-
Don't worry about that sort of thing.
Honda-san, you can just be yourself,
and take things slowly... in this house.
Tohru, you can just be yourself,
and take things slowly...
So, are you sure this is okay?
Having a girl live together with us?
What's this? Up until now
you were utterly overjoyed.
It's all right. Just as long
as neither of us get hugged.
Before I knew what was happening,
the matter had gone forward.
It feels like I'm having a dream.
But then again, I was
even borrowing clothes.
Sure enough, because it's been
closed up, it has become moldy.
It would be best to open a
window for some ventilation.
Yo!
Are you ready for me to break your neck?
Prince of Rats...
Why don't you give it up already?
You're weak, after all.
Look, you! If you look on me as being
the same as I was just a while ago,
then you're in for some pain!
Today is the day when I smash
that egotistical nose of yours!
Please, wait a moment!
Yuki-kun, I just heard a terrific
noise. By any chance has Kyo come by?
Forgive me! Are you all right!?
Ah! He turned into a cat! A cat!
It's all because I bumped into him!
--No... um... look...
--Ah! He turned into a cat! A cat!
It's all because I bumped into him!
--No... um... look...
--I hit him wrong,
and turned him into a cat!
In any case, to the hospital!
We have to get him treated by a doctor!
--Honda-san!
--Tohru-kun!
Mother, this is terrible!
Everyone is turning into animals!
Now let us circle together,
around a pleasant dinner.
Come, take today's tears, and
make them tomorrow's strength.
La, la, la...
Wonderful love and life
Adorable love and life
La, la, la...
Wonderful love and life
On the next Fruits Basket
Episode 2...
Tohru-kun, what it come down to
is that I have the Dog,
Yuki-kun has the Rat,
and he has the spirit
of the Cat possesing him.
You were just intending to erase
Honda-san's memories anyway.
Like so long ago...
I will put my trust in this Tohru-san.
Or so I said... This really is awful...
Honda Tohru will do it!