I was so very happy
when you smiled at me,
A smile that melted everything away.
Spring is still far away,
and within the cold ground,
I awaited the time when
sprouts would put forth their buds.
Even supposing today there
may have been some pain,
And though the scars of yesterday remain,
You can go on living as much
as your heart wants to believe.
You cannot be born again, although
You can go on changing yourself, and so
Let's stay together, always.
Are you really Sohma-kun's cousin?
Do you get along well with Sohma-kun?
Leave me alone!
Kyo-san...
Hey...
Would you use your head a bit
more before you take action?
When you make a fool of
yourself, it puts me out.
Are you in your right mind?
How come you're going
to a school like this...
with girls bounding
around every which-way?
Living in fear every day of
transforming is far preferable
to living like I'm in hiding,
and going to the boys'
school that Akito decided on.
I wanted to get out of the
Sohma cage, if even a little bit.
How could a Rat...
how could you understand?
I will win! I will surely win against you!
I will win against you, and
become a formal member of the Sohmas!
I won't stand for
being shunned any longer!
I'm going to win!
You mustn't!
I'm so sorry!
It's understandable why you're angry,
but you must not... must not fight!
After all, if you fight at school,
there is much that works against you...
--mmit...
Just cram it, would you!
Whether it works against me or not,
as long as I beat him,
nothing else matters!
Stay out of the way!
Who the hell are you!?
You're nasty to look at!
"Max Anger."
He hates me.
Now he completely hates me.
You really are an idiot.
Aren't you going to hit me?
There are times when it hurts
more like that, you know.
Whenever I think about how,
in a faraway mountain,
Welcome to
the Banquet
Whenever I think about how,
in a faraway mountain,
Welcome to
the Banquet
while God and the twelve animals
were enjoying their banquet,
Welcome to
the Banquet
the Cat-san had gone to bed,
dreaming about a banquet that
would not be held tomorrow...
I've made up my mind! I'm giving up
Dog-san, and I will become Cat-san!
I truly meant what I said.
Tears really did come forth.
I was so avid, that if there were
such a thing as a Cat fan club,
I would absolutely join it.
And yet, to be hated by him...
I am a fool. A real fool. Mother...
Picking up Tohru-kun's vibes...
Ah, there she is.
What are you kneeling for in a place
like this? Class is about to beg--
Ee-yow! It hurts so bad, t- the tears...!
No, really, I just bumped
the corner here, the corner...
Somehow, it looked as
though you hit it on purpose.
And so? You skipped out just like
that and came back home, then?
I want to leave this house.
It's only been three days, right?
Think of this as training
too, and put up with it.
I say nothing but
terrible things... to her.
To her? You mean to Tohru-kun?
Uh-huh. You yelled at her again with
the same tone as you always use, right?
If it gets you down afterward,
you could just not yell, you know.
Such a wretched temperament.
It's no use. I'm just not cut out for
associating and living with people.
There are people who are
like that, but in your case,
it just comes from not having
enough experience with them.
For example, with one fist,
you can break a table in half.
However, you can also make
that fist stop just short of it.
That's because you can control
by yourself how much power
to portion out your fist, right?
That's also why you were successful
when fighting with bears and stuff
--while training in the mountains.
--I didn't fight them!
Look, you. It's the same with
getting along well with other people.
It's just that this training
can't be done in the mountains.
It has to be done in the
cities, where people live.
Unless you interact with people,
hurting them and being hurt by
them as you learn about them,
as well as learn about yourself,
you'll never become the kind of person
who can be concerned about others.
Even though you may have a
black belt in the martial arts,
you still have a white belt
at getting along with others.
In order for you to become
able to cherish a girl,
who at some point is kind enough
to tell you that she likes you,
right now, you have to continue
to train, without running away.
There'll never be anyone like that.
But if there were, what would you do?
I can't even imagine.
First, I'd ask if she was crazy.
I see.
I'm home!
Ah, welcome back.
Where's Tohru-kun?
Working. She said she'll
be coming back around 11:00,
so I was thinking of
going to pick her up.
Yeah, do that for her.
There have really been a lot
of molesters around lately.
I worked a full day today too.
I wonder if everyone is asleep already.
I'll bet Kyo-san hasn't
eaten supper again tonight.
He's still angry... or what
if he left the house entirely!?
You're nasty to look at!
What will I do?
Tohru, you just be yourself.
Yes, Mother!
I will not be discouraged.
W- what was that sound?
Maybe it's... a molester...
like I've heard about...!
No!!
I couldn't say that I mistook him
for a molester! That would be rude!
But I just yelled "No!"
as loud as I could...
U- um, just a moment!
That was a practice swing.
I just happened to get lucky today.
Kyo-san, are you out for a walk?
Let's see... do you like the school?
Stop saying "san" after my name!
It irritates me. You can do without it.
--Kyo-kun...
--What do you want?
I was just trying it out.
--Don't call on me
without a reason!
--Right!
No, I mean... that's okay...
calling on me without a reason...
It's okay for you to
hang around in front of me,
and if I do anything that upsets you,
you can hit me like you just did.
Could this possibly mean...
he's trying to apologize
about what happened today?
Is that the reason why he is here?
Come to think of it,
there was that other time...
That other time,
when he might have been trying
to apologize for hurting me...
A- ahem...
I'm sorry, that wasn't it!
The reason I hit you with my bag is
because I mistook you for a molester!
Molester?
So you see, it's not
that I was upset at you!
Quite the contrary, I...
...like you!
I like the Cat from the zodiac!
That is to say, um,
I... want to be friends!
If there were one, what would you do?
A girl who says she likes you?
There isn't anything good about the Cat!
Let's hurry up and go home.
I've started to somewhat
understand Kyo-kun.
He's a little more awkward than others,
but he's certainly a
good person deep down.
He's a gentle person, who
knows when he feels sorry.
Yesterday, you know,
Kyo-kun said he was going to go
pick up Tohru-kun on his own!
Kyo-kun, you pervert!
How do you figure that!?
Yesterday was special. I won't do
it again! It'll never happen again!
Right. I'm just happy
that you're having your meal.
How is it? Is it to your liking?
--What!?
--Nothing.
You were looking at me, weren't you!?
Only looking, right?
Why would you look at me for no reason?
Do you not like it?
I hate it!
Let's play Rich Man, Poor Man!
Why don't you tell Yuki to? Damn Yuki!
If you're running away from
a fight, then you're no man!
How pathetic!
I accept your challenge to this fight!
You're going to be sorry
you did that, Yankee!
Why should I? Whoever loses has to take
on the cleaning chores for everyone here!
What a pleasant maelstrom of vibes...!
Let's invite Sohma-kun this time around,
too! Where do you suppose he's gone?
Sorry. Right now, I don't feel like
seeing anybody, so I have to say--
No! I don't want to hear it! Yuki-kun!
I, uh...
Yuki-kun, you are nice...
...but there's something
about you that rejects others.
Everyone says so!
"Yuki-kun is 'special'," they say.
"An 'ordinary' girl isn't good
enough to match up with Yuki-kun."
"Revolution!"
Why, you! What kind of dirty tricks
are you pulling, you rotten boy!?
That's how the rules go!
Let's see, a Revolution makes
the strong cards weak, so...
Special move--Reverse Revolution!
--You've had it now, Sohma!
--Nice going, Hanajima-san!
Whoa, how embarrassing!
Shut up, you guys!
This game's just getting started!
Yuki-kun, there's something
about you that rejects others.
Rich Man, Poor Man, huh?
I know the rules, but I've never played.
I just learned how to play
from Uo-chan myself.
Next time, let's play it together!
So, he was the Poor Man today, then?
Um, we'll help you, too!
No! My loss is my loss.
But...
Next time, though, I'm
going to win for sure!
And of course, I will beat you too!
Don't you get tired of
always saying that?
It is my conviction to win
against you! My objective!
And having you always badgering me
with it is my annoyance! My misfortune!
Your attitude of looking down
upon others makes me sick!
Your overly simplistic way
of thinking makes me sick.
They're fighting again.
They get along worse than just being
Rat-san and Cat-san accounts for.
Come to think of it, there
was that time earlier...
I will win against you, and
become a member of the Sohmas!
Could those words indeed mean
that if Kyo-kun beats Sohma-kun,
he will be allowed to join the zodiac?
In other words...
In other words, Cat-san will be included,
and the Twelve will become Thirteen!
That would be wonderful!
Damn you! I'll pulverize you!
However, fighting will not do. Not at all.
Um, Kyo-kun--
Prepare yourself, you cold-blooded rat!
Just looking at you gets on my nerves!
Sohma-kun...
Damn it all...
Why can't I beat him?
Today's move was a particularly
rough one. He must be in a bad mood.
As much as Sohma-kun is
considerate towards others,
he may be the kind of person who keeps
his own feelings shut up inside him.
Say, guess what? There's this
incredibly good-looking kid outside.
I wonder, is it a boy or a girl?
Oh my, how very lowbrow!
Could that be...?
Sohma-kun!
Hey there! What a hard worker you are!
D- did you come all the
way just to pick me up?
Mm-hm. This is a dangerous
time for girls, and all.
Thank you very much! Sohma-kun,
you and Kyo-kun are both kind!
Well, shall we go?
S- Sohma-kun...!
Um, if there's anything
gloomy weighing on your mind,
please tell me about it, okay.
When you have a bad dream,
they say it brings good luck
to talk to someone, and all.
So if I'm okay with you, and you want
to stamp that gloom out, I don't m--!
Hey, there! Don't go hangin'
'round here, get on home, youngsters!
?I can' go back to my house at all...??
...I don't mind, but maybe I'm just
adding to your gloom instead...
No. It's my fault for
having this nature about me.
When I was at my parents' house,
it was like I was in a cage, being kept
watched on by the main house and Akito.
I was surrounded by ordinary people,
and yearned for an ordinary life.
That's why I left the house and
began going to a coed high school.
However, as it turns out,
I haven't left the cage at all.
I'm still living in a
Sohma's house, same as before,
and I can't associate
with others very well.
It's not that I...
mean to reject others, but there's
something about me that's awkward.
And since I'm like this, I can't
escape my feelings of inferiority,
or my being frightened.
But Kyo is different. He may not take
well to those who he's unfamiliar with,
but I think once you get to know him,
he's the type of person
that draws others in.
Even if he can't
become one of the zodiac,
I think it's better for one to be able to
naturally get along with ordinary people.
I wanted to be like that too.
That's why it gets on my nerves.
When I see for myself how
Kyo wants to join the Sohmas...
I wonder what it is about me
that wants to leave there.
Sohma-kun, you too have the
power to draw people in.
So many girls say they like
you, and that you're nice.
I'm only nice because I
want to be liked by them.
It's like I'm giving them candy because
I want to be in their circle of friends.
I'm only being nice for my own
sake. Maybe that's hypocritical...
So--
This was sure sudden. There was
nothing in the weather forecast about it.
This is terrible!
Sohma-kun...!
What's so terrible?
A farm?
It's more like a family vegetable garden.
Sohma-kun, you did this?
Mm-hmm. This is my secret base.
This is wonderful! I get it now!
You have to protect the base from
this harsh wind and rain, right?
I'll do whatever little
I can to help you out!
Honda-san, you sure are kind!
Ah, you can't mean it!
This is the first time I've ever had
anyone say that to me! I'm so happy!
Ah, but what if I too
am being hypocritical,
and only doing this so I will
look like a good person to others?
No, Honda-san, I
think it's in your nature.
Still, my mother always said it's
better to believe than to doubt.
People aren't born with kindness,
you know, she would say.
Things like our appetites, or material
desires--that's what we're all born with.
It just means that they
are instinctive for living.
Kindness is something that
develops, just like our bodies do,
and the heart that grows inside
us is our conscience, she'd say.
That's why it takes on different
forms, depending on the person.
Desire is something that everyone is
born with, so it's easy to comprehend.
But kindness is like something which
people have to hand-make for themselves,
so it is easily misunderstood, or
taken to be hypocrisy, you see.
When I heard that,
I was excited to think that people
had kindnesses that were of different
shapes--like they
could be round, or pointy.
Sohma-kun, your kindness is like a
candle. Your light shines brightly.
When it does, I become
happy, and want to smile.
Ah, a candle must seem
pretty weird, doesn't it?
Mm-mm! It's just--I'm really pathetic.
Here I am a guy, yet the way I
was going on about everything...
I'm happy you did. Sohma-kun, for you to
tell me so many things about yourself,
I feel that we are getting
along that much better.
Excuse me! I will continue
with my duty to protect the base!
Doubting is easy, it's something all
of us can do. Tohru, you believe.
Become the kind of girl
who can believe in others.
That will surely...
surely lend strength to someone.
We defended it to the last!
But we came out of it pretty ragged.
Is there anything that looks
ready to pick right now?
Perhaps the leeks are ready to be eaten.
Leeks?
Leeks... leeks...
Honda-san...
Next time, I'll give
Rich Man, Poor Man a try.
By all means! But I thought
you weren't interested in it.
Mm-mm. It's just that it is so noisy,
I felt hesitant. But I will try.
Little by little is okay, but I will
get better at socializing with people.
It'll be all right! Hana-chan
and Uo-chan are very good people.
They are the friends
that I can take pride in!
Besides, Sohma-kun, you
seem like you'd be good at it,
everyone will be delighted
over a new challenge!
Yeah. I'm not going to give in!
I got the feeling that this was the
first time I saw Sohma-kun really smile.
Thank you for waiting!
I hate leeks!
And not just leeks either, right?
You hate onions and miso too, right?
If the miso is in miso
soup, that's no problem!
I did not know that. I'm sorry. I will
hurry and fix some other dish, okay?
Eat!
Maybe there isn't anything that can be
done about how badly they get along.
However, could it be possible
that there's something about
Sohma-kun that appeals to Kyo?
Yuki-kun, Kyo-kun is unconscious already.
If they could understand
that about each other,
they would get along better, maybe...
I... guess I just
misunderstood you. I'm sorry.
Me too. Let's go on, forever
deepening our friendship!
Somehow, that's scary too!
Now let us circle together,
around a pleasant dinner.
Come, take today's tears, and
make them tomorrow's strength.
La, la, la...
Wonderful love and life
Adorable love and life
La, la, la...
Wonderful love and life
On the next Fruits Basket
Episode 4...
My name is Sohma Kagura.
Sohma Kagura-san? What a cute girl!
In fact, Kagura has kept saying she
would marry Kyo since she was little.
Right. Kagura-san is incredible.
When she's here, things go badly for me.
She never, ever
understands what's going on.
I think it's amazing that someone
could come to like someone else so much.