Hey, Mop-Top!
Sir!
[KEITH] What do they
call you, maggot?
[ARMIN] Armin Arlelt,
from Shinganshina, sir!
Wow, seriously?
Why would your parents
curse you with
such a dumb name?
[ARMIN] It was
my grandfather, sir!
Cadet Arlelt! Why is
a runt like you here?
To help humanity
overcome the Titans!
That is delightful to hear!
You're gonna be a
great light snack for him!
Row Three, About Face, runt!
What do you call yourself?
Sir. My name is Thomas Wagner,
I'm from the Trost district!
I can't hear you!
[THOMAS] I'm from
Trost, sir, my name--
Look at him go.
The man is a master
when it comes to
fresh-faced recruits.
That takes me back.
Is a pathetic worm like you
the best Karaness has to offer?
Sir! I'm afraid
that's the case, sir!
Tell your backwoods--
But what's the point
of all the intimidation?
It's a Rite of Passage.
Through stress and denigration
we revert them
into blank slates.
From there, we can mold them
bit by bit into proper soldiers.
He is the first
step in that process.
We seem to really excel
at that back home, sir!
[KEITH] Row Four, About Face!
[YOUNG INSTRUCTOR] There
are some he's passing by.
[INSTRUCTOR] A drill instructor
is nothing compared to
[INSTRUCTOR] what those
recruits have seen.
[INSTRUCTOR] They were there.
Witnesses to the hell of
[INSTRUCTOR] the Titan
attack two years ago.
[INSTRUCTOR] You can
read it in their faces.
[INSTRUCTOR] C'mon. Let's go.
What do we have over here?
Jean Kirschtein, sir.
From the Trost District!
And why're you here, cadet?
To join the Military Police,
sir. The best of the best.
[KEITH] That's nice. You want
to live in the interior, do you?
Yes!
[KEITH] No one told
you to sit, Recruit!
If you can't handle
this, Kirschtein,
then forget about
joining the Military Police!
What the hell is wrong with
your face, you smiling idiot?
Marco Bodt at your
service, sir, from Jinae.
South side of Wall Rose. I aim
to join the Military Police
and give life and limb
in service to the king!
Well then. That makes you
an idealistic fool. And a rube.
[KEITH] You want the truth?
The only use the king has for
your life and limbs
are as Titan fodder.
Hey, Cue-ball. You're up next!
Oh, me? Sir! Conny Springer,
from Ragako village, sir!
You have it backwards,
Conny Springer.
That was the first
thing you were taught.
This salute
represents the resolve
in your heart to
fight those bent on
the systematic
destruction of our people!
Is your heart
on your right side?
[chewing]
Hey, you there. What
do you think you're doing?
[chewing]
You are officially
on my shit list.
Just who in the hell are you?
[swallow]
Sasha Braus from Dauper
village, at your service.
Reporting for duty, sir!
Sasha Braus, huh?
And what is that you're
clutching in your right hand?
A steamed potato!
It sat there in the mess
hall begging to be eaten. Sir!
The theft, I understand.
But here? Why eat
it here of all places?
It looked quite delicious.
And it was getting cold.
So I gave it shelter
in my stomach, sir.
Why? I can't comprehend.
Why would you eat that potato?
Are you asking me
why people eat potatoes?
I'm surprised
you don't know, sir.
Here sir. Have half.
"Have half?" Really?
Man, I thought Sadies
was gonna kill Potato Girl.
I know. What a
helluva first day.
[EREN] It's funny. Being
told to run 'til the sun sets
[EREN] didn't seem to
bother her nearly as much as
[EREN] losing meal privileges
for the next five days.
I think she said
that she's from Dauper.
If I remember right,
that's a small hunting village
up in the mountains.
Hey, what's that?
[MINA] They're dropouts. They'd
prefer to work in the fields.
[ARMIN] But. It's
only the first day.
[EREN] That's the way it is.
[EREN] If you can't handle the
pressure, you've gotta leave.
I can't believe anyone would
rather pull plants than fight.
I know about some of us,
but you never mentioned
where you were from, Eren.
The same as Armin.
From Shinganshina.
Oh, wow. That means.
You saw it. You
were there that day.
Huh? Quiet!
The Colossal one?
Did you see him?
Yeah. Yeah, I did.
Yeah, okay? I saw the big guy.
Whoa, seriously?
Okay, exactly how tall was he?
He stuck his head
over the outer wall.
Whoa, wait! I heard he stepped
over the wall completely.
So did I!
That was the rumor
in my village, too!
Nah. He was big,
but not that big.
So what did it look like?
It had a mouth like a corpse.
And no skin, just muscles.
And the Armored Titan? The one
that broke through Wall Maria?
Is that what they're
calling it? In all the panic,
[EREN] it was just
another Titan to me.
No way. So,
what were they like?
C'mon. That's enough questions,
alright? I'm sure he'd rather
not relive everything
he went through.
Sorry. We didn't mean to--
[EREN] It's not like that!
[chewing]
Those stupid Titans. They're
really not that big of a deal.
If we focus on mastering the
Omni-Directional Mobility Gear
they give us, then
it's Titan payback time!
[EREN] I've waited years
to be trained as a soldier.
[EREN] All of a sudden,
the reality is sinking in.
I'm joining the Scout
Regiment. Then I'm sending
the Titans back to hell.
I'm gonna butcher them all.
[JEAN] Hey, are you
crazy or something?
Not that it's my
business, but signing up
for reconnaissance is
like a death sentence.
I guess we'll see.
Or at least I will.
You seem content hiding
in the interior with the MPs.
Look, I'm just speaking
honestly here, kid.
I think it's better
than being some loud mouthed
braggart tough-guy
wannabe pretending
he's not as piss-scared
as the rest of us.
Are you trying to pick a fight?
[MARCO] Stop it you guys!
Alright, sure. Makes
no difference to me.
[BOTH] Huh?
Hey. I apologize.
Sorry for calling you names
and dismissing
your choice of career.
Put 'er there,
kid. Whaddaya say?
Right. Yeah, I'm sorry as well.
[JEAN] Umm. Excuse me?
I-- Uh. I just
wanted-- I mean.
I've never seen anyone
like you before. I mean, uh.
I'm-- I'm sorry. You have
really beautiful black hair.
Thank you.
Would you lay off?
It's no big deal!
It's just that
you get so worked up
you don't think things through.
Again with this?
[EREN] If you
insist on worrying,
[EREN] worry about
how long your hair is.
[EREN] It's gonna catch
up with you in a bad way
[EREN] when we
start on the ODMs.
Okay, fine. I'll cut it.
[MIKASA] How short
should I go, do you think?
[humming]
What the hell? Leave
my clothes alone, dammit!
[CONNY] What did you wipe on me?
Don't worry. Just my trust.
I'm... finished.
[wheezing]
[sniffing]
[shriek]
Could it be? It's bread!
I'm sorry there isn't
more. It's all I could take.
Hey, hang on. You really should
drink a little water first.
You-- You're a Goddess,
aren't you? Glory unto you!
Hey. Just what are
you two girls up to?
Well, uh. She's been running all
day. Without any food or water.
I see. So you're
trying to be "nice," huh?
Eh?
What's the point of breakin'
the rules for Potato Girl?
That mindless act of kindness
gets you absolutely nowhere.
Whatever.
[YMIR] Let's just
get her to bed already.
I'm confused.
Are you being nice?
I'm helping her so that she'll
owe me one in the future.
I intend to make
use of her stupidity.
It's aptitude test
time, so listen up!
There is no place for you
here if you cannot perform!
Fail, and be shipped
to the fields.
[INSTRUCTOR] We're just
drilling the fundamentals here.
You can still determine
a Cadet's knack
for it just by watching.
Like her. Completely steady.
[INSTRUCTOR] She
inherently knows what to do,
[INSTRUCTOR] and how
to make it happen.
[INSTRUCTOR] That's what
aptitude is all about.
[INSTRUCTOR] I'd
say we have several
[INSTRUCTOR] capable
cadets this year.
And what about this guy?
That's precisely
why we run these tests.
He proves that drive
and dedication do not
[INSTRUCTOR] always
translate into capability.
What is your major
malfunction, Jaeger?
Straighten yourself up!
[snickering]
[EREN] Why am I--
How do I work this thing?
This can't be happening!
Just remember the basics
and you should be fine.
No need to try
any fancy maneuvers.
Just focus on your balance.
Then distribute your
weight evenly between
the belts on your
waist and your legs.
Loosen up your
stance a little bit.
If I could do it,
I know that you can!
Okay. A loose
stance, but balanced.
Let's give it a shot, Armin.
Hey, Daz. He was talking big
about butchering all the Titans,
but he got real quiet after
ODM training, didn't he?
I guess it's the fields
for him tomorrow.
Can't keep wasting
food on the useless.
Eren.
[ARMIN] Worrying
won't solve a thing.
[ARMIN] There's still time
to get some practice in
[ARMIN] come morning.
[EREN] How pathetic. How
am I supposed to kill 'em
[EREN] if I can't
even stand up straight?
[MIKASA] It might be
time to let that dream die.
Whaddaya mean?
I think you should give up
this attempt to be a soldier.
There's a lot more
to fighting and combat
than just throwing
your life away in vain.
What're you saying? After
everything we saw that day,
after what happened to my mom.
You're crazy if you think
I'm just going to walk away.
I get it. But it doesn't
matter how determined you are.
It-- Wait, what do you mean?
Because whether or not
you're fit to be a
soldier isn't up to you.
You misunderstand.
I'm not saying you should
return to the
fields by yourself.
I wouldn't dream of it.
Because wherever you go.
I'm gonna go with you--
[SASHA] So. Uh.
Are you saying...
[SASHA] that you're not
going to finish that?
[CONNY] What's the trick to
posture control? Hard to say.
Guess I got the "gift". You've
just gotta feel it, y'know?
I'm trying to
figure out your trick.
You've screwed
upevery way imaginable,
short of an accidental
equipment-related asphyxiation.
Please guys. You gotta
help me, I'm begging you!
That's funny. Wasn't
it just yesterday you said
"if you can't handle the
pressure, you gotta leave?"
[CONNY] No, wait. Or was it
"if you're a complete idiot,
you gotta leave?"
Something like that.
Oh, come on.
I heard from everyone
you're both really good at it!
[EREN] Bertholdt! Reiner!
Sorry kid. But there
isn't any special trick
to just hanging there.
Not to be harsh,
but if it's advice you want,
I'm not really the guy.
Alright.
[ARMIN] Let's just hope
it comes to you tomorrow.
Hold on. Aren't the two of you
originally from Shiganshina?
Yeah, that's right.
Then you know first-hand
how terrifying they are.
Why on earth would
you want to be soldiers?
I didn't see
the things. Eren did.
He saw their
bloodlust first hand,
before anyone realized
how bad it was.
And I-- I knew I couldn't sit
idly by as the royal government
forced the citizenry
into the failed
territory retrieval operation.
[BERTHOLDT] I see.
So where are
the two of you from?
Oh, Reiner and I? We were
both from a mountain village
just Southeast of Wall Maria.
But. Then that means.
[BERTHOLDT] Yeah. Unlike the
more prosperous river towns,
[BERTHOLDT] our village
didn't receive word right away.
[BERTHOLDT]
The Titans were on us
[BERTHOLDT] before we
even knew what was going on.
It happened at dawn. All the
livestock were so restless.
Soon after, we heard
these strange rumblings
that just became
louder and louder.
[BERTHOLDT] Eventually, I
realized those rumblings were
[BERTHOLDT] the sound of
death getting closer. I, uh...
[BERTHOLDT] I looked
out my window, and--
After that, well, uh.
Everything is just a blur.
I think we all just panicked.
Hey. Easy now.
You're just getting
yourself worked up again.
Sorry. Basically, what I've
been trying to say is this.
The four of us aren't
like the rest of-- of them.
"Them" who?
The others here who've never
been witness to
the Titan's horror.
Hey.
[chattering and laughter]
[BERTHOLDT] Most of
them are here for show.
To do just what
society expects.
In a world where you're
labeled a coward if you choose
fieldwork by the
time you turn twelve,
propriety demands our service.
With that said, I'm really
no different from the others.
[BERTHOLDT] I joined the
ranks hoping for assignment to
[BERTHOLDT] the Military Police.
Tucked away in the Interior.
[BERTHOLDT] If that doesn't
work out, I'll give up entirely.
[BERTHOLDT] I don't really have
the fortitude for anything else.
[ARMIN] There's no
shame in caring about
[ARMIN] your life,
Bertholdt. We all do.
Do we?
[REINER] I'm going
to return to the home
[REINER] that was taken from me.
That's all I care about now.
I will do it. No matter what.
[BERTHOLDT] What about
you? Why did you sign up?
Why'd I join?
I decided I have to kill them.
[EREN] I won't stop
'til every single
[EREN] Titan is
dead and rotting.
Dead. Every last one.
[REINER] You saw what those
monsters are capable of,
[REINER] and you still
want to take them on?
[EREN] Damn right. It's just,
after screwing up the training,
[EREN] I don't know if
I'm cut out to be a soldier.
[REINER] We'll take it from
step one: Belt Adjustment.
[REINER] By tomorrow,
you'll be an expert.
I know you've got what it
takes. I can see it in you.
Am I wrong here?
No! I won't fail. Thank you,
Reiner. Thank you.
Eren Jaeger. Are you ready?
[EREN] Yes sir! I'm
going to do it. I have to!
[EREN] I may not be
as talented as the rest.
[EREN] But nobody,
nobody, has more guts!
Proceed!
[EREN] The moment of truth. I
won't fail again. To hell with
[EREN] working the damn
fields! I'm not giving up.
[EREN] Not without a fight!
[cheering]
[EREN] I did it?
No, I'm doing it!
[gasp]
No! Not yet!
Once more! I can do it!
Lower him.
I-- I'm finished.
Wagner! Please exchange
belts with Mr. Jaeger.
Huh? Yes sir!
[KEITH] Your equipment
was defective.
If given a piece of
functional gear,
you might not be
worthless after all.
[KEITH] Quartermaster didn't
notice this broken clasp.
[KEITH] Might have to
visit the Supply Depot
[KEITH] and crack
a couple skulls.
He-- He still did it. Even while
wearing that busted gear.
Amazing.
So, you mean I--
I didn't wash out?
You made the cut.
Now keep training, cadet!
[EREN] I did it.
I really did it!
[EREN] Check it out,
Mikasa! I'm doing it!
[EREN] I can fight the Titans!
[EREN] You don't
have to worry about me!
[EREN] Not anymore!
It seems like
things worked out for him.
Look, his eyes are
saying "check me out!"
They're not.
His eyes are saying he doesn't
have to leave me. Not anymore.
[KEITH] Grisha. Today
should bring you pride.
[KEITH] Your son is a soldier!
♪
[NARRATOR] After
graduating from the Cadets,
[NARRATOR] Eren sees mankind
begin to restore its dignity.
[NARRATOR]
"We can beat the Titans."
[NARRATOR] The moment
he feels certain of this,
[NARRATOR] humanity
is given a grim reminder.