[NARRATOR] And just like
that. Everything changed.
[NARRATOR] At that terrible
moment, in our hearts, we knew.
[NARRATOR] Home was
a pen; humanity, cattle.
♪
Hyah! Hyah! Hyah!
[MAN] Moment of truth,
people! It's on us!
[MAN] Either we secure
this ground as mankind's
first stronghold beyond
the walls, or we die!
Target approaching!
♪
[MAN] Split into
five groups, now!
Group one will act as the bait!
All squadrons, engage
omni-directional mobility gear!
[MAN] Hit it
from every angle!
Ahhhhhh!
[MAN] For my brothers!
For humanity!
[growl]
[gasp]
[BOY] Mikasa. Hey.
[MIKASA] We should get back.
[BOY] Um, where are we exactly?
[MIKASA] Try asking me
again when you're awake.
[EREN] I'm up, I--
I just-- I dunno.
[BOY] It's like the dream
I was having went on forever.
[BOY] It's gone now.
What was it about?
Eren, have--
Have you been crying?
Harken! These walls are
a bulwark gifted by God!
Riven rock? Stone?
Mortar? No, my brethren!
They are bastions of faith!
The will of heaven manifest!
Do me a favor, huh? Don't
let anyone know I was crying.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Still, though.
You don't even remember why?
Might want have
your dad look into that.
Right, 'cause tearing up
is usually a medical thing.
[HANNES] Somebody
messin' with you?
Hey Mr. Hannes.
Or you just get
on Mikasa's bad side?
No! What are you
even talking about?
Ugh! You smell like a tavern!
[laughing] If only
tears were cups of ale.
Of course.
You kids care for a swig?
Aren't you, uh, on watch?
Yup! Watchin' the
ol' gate we are.
Thirsty work, playin' sentry.
Pinochle only goes so far to
chase off the boredom.
Li'l nip now and then keeps us
all in our courage for a spell.
Perks of being a guard, eh?
How do you expect to fight if
you're so loose on your feet?
Huh? Now why on earth
would I have to fight?
Why do you think? What if
they break through the walls?
We'd be sitting
ducks on your watch!
[market chattering]
[HANNES] Eren. Kid. Please.
Use your inside voice.
[laugh] The doc's kid
has some fire in him!
Listen, the only thing they've
done to the wall in the past
hundred years is scratch at it.
I have the feelin' if they
get it in their big heads
to do somethin' else,
we'll be more 'n ready for 'em.
A feeling? What have
any of you actually done
to be ready for 'em?
Dad says you've
gotta stay sharp!
Ah, good Doctor
Jaeger. Yeah, well.
[HANNES] Can't argue with
a man who single-handedly
[HANNES] spared us
from the plague.
[HANNES] Thing is, he's
talkin' about his scalpel.
[HANNES] What we do
isn't half as important.
Hey, no disrespect to your
father, but a soldier's time
beyond the wall kinda tends
to put the whole issue
into a different perspective.
[HANNES] You see 'em
groping around out there,
[HANNES] mindless, dead-eyed.
[EREN] Wait a minute.
Sounds to me like you
[EREN] don't even think
they're all that dangerous.
[HANNES] Eh.
Oh great! Then at least
have the decency to stop
calling yourselves a garrison;
people might get the wrong idea!
[laughing] Good point.
Look at it this way, huh?
If a garrison's actually doing
what people think it
oughta, we're up a creek.
Personally I take a lot of stock
in being called a freeloader,
it means things are good. It's
how I can measure peace of mind.
[EREN] Good? We live in a cage.
All we do is eat and sleep.
[EREN] That's it. End of story.
We have the peace
of mind of livestock.
[laughing] Man, you were right
about the kid havin' fire!
Careful not to cry it out.
[ELITE MAN] You coming
back to the game or what?
Yeah.
[HANNES] Hey! Where you goin'?
[HUGO] The mouth on that kid.
He's just a kid.
Tends to dream bigger than
life really wants him to.
Eren. You should let
the Scout Regiment thing go.
Seriously? Why does everybody
think they're a joke?
What people think about
'em isn't really the issue.
[bell ringing]
[EREN] Perfect timing!
They're back!
We can make it if we hurry. Get
a move on! I want a good view!
[chattering]
Argh. Can't see squat.
[distant chattering]
[gasp]
[CITIZEN] Sure taken
a hit, haven't they?
[CITIZEN] Yeah. Rest of 'em
got eaten. That's what happens
[CITIZEN] when pride takes
you outside the walls.
[WOMAN'S VOICE] Moses? Moses?
Beg your pardon. Where is my
son? He should be with you all.
Oh, please tell me he made it!
I wish I had better
news. Give it to her.
[gasp]
[crying]
I'm sorry. It's all
that was left of him.
[crying]
He-- He did good,
yes? He was brave?
Tell me my son stood his
ground to the bitter end.
That his death
meant something!
Tell me his sacrifice
gave us a better chance!
He was brave!
[KEITH] But. His
sacrifice meant nothing.
[KEITH] So with all our
losses. It's ever the same.
The day was lost!
We have nothing!
[KEITH] Your son died because
of me! I sent him to his death!
[KEITH] I sent all
of them to their deaths!
And there's nothing
to show for it!
All of it amounts to nothing!
[chatter]
[COMMONER] Uplifting, huh.
Oh, sure. Nothing like seeing
our hard-earned taxes go toward
keeping those bastards fat
and happy on human gristle.
[COMMONER] You little punk!
[EREN] What are
you doing? Let me go!
Yeah, that's right!
You'd better run!
[EREN] Alright, I get
it! Stop already!
[EREN] Oh great! Firewood
everywhere! Perfect!
So. Are you still
bound and determined
to become one
of them? The Scouts?
[EREN] Just help
me pick these up.
[MIKASA] Like there
was much to begin with.
Hey, we're home.
Welcome back, kids.
Wow. Somebody worked
hard to keep us in fuel
for the next several days.
Eh. Whatever.
What was that for?
Your earlobe's red, which means
you've got something to hide.
Mikasa helped you
again, now didn't she?
Hey. Where you off to, Dad?
A patient?
Yes. Some folks
in the Interior.
I should be back
in about a week or so.
So, um, Eren's thinking
about joining the Scouts.
Way to keep a secret, mouth!
Get that ridiculous
thought out of your head
this instant, young man!
No son of mine is
going to be fodder!
Do I make myself
absolutely clear?
Stop yelling at me!
Don't you dare--
It's a nightmare, Eren.
The Outside. You
really have no idea.
Yeah, I get it, okay? But it's
gotta be better than this life!
I'm not stupid; I know
it's ugly out there,
I know there's death
around every corner. But--
We can't just give up on it.
'Cause otherwise this
nightmare's never gonna end!
I see.
Excuse me. I'll be
late for the ferry.
Darling, wait! Scold the boy,
for heaven's sake!
Scold him? Dear, please.
Think this through.
Mere words won't hold back
the boy's curiosity. Eren.
Behave while I'm gone
and I'll let you in on
what I've been doing
in the cellar. Agreed?
Yes sir, you got it!
[EREN] Have a good trip!
[CARLA] I meant what I said.
[EREN] What?
The whole idea is
just irresponsible.
Huh? Irresponsible? So,
what? It's more grown up to
settle for living in fear
behind some stupid wall
your whole pointless life?
Eren!
Mikasa.
The boy needs to be
protected from himself.
Promise me whatever happens
I can count on
you to have his back!
[BULLY] [snickering] Where's
the sacrilege now, huh?
[BULLY] Or does your
philosophy say it's wrong
[EREN] to fight back, too?
As a matter of fact, it does.
I'd rather take a few lumps
than brawl like a beast!
Oh, so now I'm a beast?
Take a good hard look
at yourself and tell me
you're not acting like one!
You resort to violence
because your brain's
the size of a walnut!
[ARMIN] So pummel me all
you want! I've already won!
Yeah, well you know
what? I'm a sore loser!
[EREN] Back off!
It's Eren!
Hey, lookie here!
Back for more?
You'd think he would
have learned his lesson.
Give this one to me.
[BULLY] Oh crap.
She's with him.
Run! Just run!
Heh-heh. That's all it takes.
One look. I'm just that scary.
Well, one of you is.
Where'd they get you, Armin?
It's alright. Thank you.
Okay.
[ARMIN] Oh, they just heard
me rattling on about how
[ARMIN] mankind's future
lay beyond the walls.
[ARMIN] Doubt they understood
half of it, but still.
[EREN] Idiots.
Why's it gotta be this way?
Why can't people
just let us dream?
The walls are a powerful
idea. We've survived for
a hundred years because of them.
No one's keen on tempting fate.
I may not agree
with that sentiment,
but I can see where
they're coming from.
It's human nature, Eren.
When all's said and done,
the government's policies
are a reflection of our fear.
Yeah, the rest of the herd's
maybe. I say to hell with them!
Someone's gonna hear you.
Keep it down.
What do I care? You'll
rat me out either way.
What?
I never promised you anything.
Your folks know
about the Scouts?
Basically. And they're
not too pleased.
Yeah. Big shock.
It's sad. What most people
here are willing to settle for
in exchange for some fleeting
sense of security, you know?
Momma!
And make no mistake,
it absolutely is fleeting.
The walls can't hold forever.
[children playing]
Only a matter of time.
[ARMIN] What was that?
[EREN] I dunno!
I'm tellin' ya, it
came from over there!
Armin, what are you doing?
Talk to me! What's going on?
Some kinda explosion or--?
♪
[ARMIN]No! That's impossible!
That wall's fifty meters high!
[EREN] Oh god.
[EREN] It's a titan!
♪
[scream]
[screaming]
♪
It-- It blasted a hole.
Like it was kicking a rock.
[CITIZEN] Run for your lives!
[CITIZEN] They've
breeched the wall!
[screaming]
[gasp] We have to go.
[gasp] Eren! No!
Our house is in that direction!
Mom's all by herself!
Mikasa!
This-- This is the end.
They're inside.
We-- Every last one of us
is going to be devoured!
[wailing and sobbing]
[sobbing]
Our house is fine; our house
is fine. You'll turn the corner
and it's gonna be standing there
in one piece, just like always!
[EREN] Mom!
Eren, wait!
It's okay! Mikasa,
grab that end
and hoist with
everything you got!
[gasp]
Oh, no.
♪
Hurry up, dammit!
[MIKASA] I'm trying!
It's them. You've got
to get out of here!
Eren! Just take
Mikasa and run! Now!
I want to, more than anything!
[EREN] But first I
need you on your feet!
Sweetie, listen to me.
My legs have been crushed.
Even if you could get me
out of here, I can't run.
There's no time.
Whatever! I can carry you!
Will you just shut up and listen
to me for once in your life?
[CARLA] One thing I'm asking
you! One thing!
[CARLA] Mikasa, make him!
[MIKASA] I can't.
You want all
three of us to die?
Hannes!
Take the children and
get them out of here!
Come on, Carla; that's
not our only option.
Hey, I'm a trained soldier.
My skill set is killin'
Titans and saving lives!
[CARLA] No, wait!
Don't do this! Please!
[thinking] Nothing fancy.
Just take it down.
Get all three of
'em out of harm's way.
Make good on the debt you owe!
[gasp]
[EREN] No! What are you doing?
Put me down, you bastard!
Thank you, Hannes.
[EREN] Wait! No!
[EREN] We can't
just leave her! Mom!
I love you! You hear me?
[CARLA] Stay alive!
♪
[crying]
Don't leave me.
♪
Stop it! Nooooo!
[NARRATOR] And just like
that. Everything changed.
[NARRATOR] At that terrible
moment, in our hearts, we knew.
[NARRATOR] Home was
a pen. Humanity, cattle.
[NARRATOR] Shiganshina
crumbles. Prayers are useless.
[NARRATOR] Tears are absurd.
Death agonies are nothing.
[NARRATOR] When total
ruin is your reality,
[NARRATOR] all that's left
of any value is revenge.