[NARRATOR] They first appeared
over a hundred years ago.
[NARRATOR] Giant,
humanoid creatures with
[NARRATOR] a taste
for our blood.
[NARRATOR] The brute strength
of these aberrations trumped
[NARRATOR] an average
person's many times over.
[NARRATOR] We were shoved to
[NARRATOR] the brink of
extinction almost overnight.
[NARRATOR] The survivors erected
Walls Maria, Rose, and Sina;
[NARRATOR] withdrawing behind
them in frightened huddles for
[NARRATOR] what was to be
a century of uneasy peace.
[NARRATOR] And then...
Caw!
"'Til then a man apart
from God. O wretched was I.
And driven e'en as
a plough by avarice."
[PREACHER] "Now, thou behold'st,
am I here punished for it.
[PREACHER] Punished
by the justice of God."
[PREACHER] "Where covetousness
leads, thou sees't bourn.
[PREACHER] Upon the penance
of these writhing souls,
[PREACHER] the Mountain
holds no greater pain!"
[PREACHER] "As greed has drowned
our love for every good,
[PREACHER] every right,
so justice here doth chain."
[panting]
[screaming] Please! No!
[PREACHER] "Tethered, captive,
are; merged with the clay.
[PREACHER] And thus to remain
so long as it pleases The Lord:
[PREACHER] fraught, fixed,
earthen in heart and limb."
"What else may heav'nly grace
do for sins as ours?" Huh?
[PREACHER] "For we lifted not
our eye to heights bequeathed,
[PREACHER] and like the plou--"
[heavy breathing]
[punch]
[HANNES] Damn it! Stop!
[EREN] You son of a bitch!
We could've saved her!
We almost had her out!
Why did you come? Why?
[HANNES] I told you to stop!
Eren!
[HANNES] Look...
[HANNES] There's nothing
you could've done for her,
[HANNES] you understand?
You're a kid; you're weak.
[HANNES] I'm worse.
When push came to shove,
I was too frightened
to hold my ground.
Your mother died because
I'm a damn coward!
[HANNES] I'm sorry.
It's the same
thing all over again.
[screaming]
Hurry up! Keep your
eye on the Gate!
[HUGO] Drop everything,
find the ferry nearest you
[HUGO] and climb aboard
for all you're worth! Move it!
[HUGO] These things aren't
gonna give you a head start!
[NARRATOR] So-called Outlier
Districts like Shiganshina
[NARRATOR]  jut out like thorns
at vital spots along Wall Maria.
[NARRATOR] Their basic
function is to streamline
[NARRATOR] troop dispersal
and keep security costs down by
[NARRATOR] drawing Titans
into specific areas.
[NARRATOR] The calculated
design flaw in all
[NARRATOR] Outlier Districts
is that they have only
[NARRATOR] a single gate
through which its citizens
[NARRATOR] are able
to retreat deeper inward
[NARRATOR] should
the need arise.
No personal belongings!
We need to make
as much room as possible!
Armin. You best have a seat.
I will. Just keeping
an eye out for my friends.
There they are!
[ARMIN] Eren.
I wouldn't try
to call out just now.
Give 'em their space. God only
knows what they've just seen.
[panicking]
Stop dragging your
feet! Snap out of it!
I need those canons loaded!
C'mon! They're
headed right for us!
[screaming]
[panting]
[MALE CITIZEN] This isn't
real. This is a nightmare.
[FEMALE CITIZEN] God help us.
God help us. God help us.
[panic and shouting]
[MALE CITIZEN]
Hey! What are you doing?
[MALE CITIZEN] What are the
rest of us supposed to do?
[ELITE] I'm sorry,
it's at full capacity!
[FEMALE CITIZEN]
You can't do this! Please!
[FEMALE CITIZEN] At least
let our children on board!
Look, there's nothing
we can do! Push off, now!
[FEMALE CITIZEN]
Don't leave us!
[MALE CITIZEN]
There's still room!
[panic]
♪
What are you aiming at? Have
you got rocks in your head?
Sir. With respect, they're
old as sin and not designed
for accuracy to begin with!
[HUGO] You gonna give me
attitude or you gonna reload?
[HUGO] Stop whining
and do your job!
[ELITE] What's the point?
No. The Inner Gate.
I'm not getting left behind.
[ELITE] Retreat or die!
Hey!
[HANNES] Wait! Are you out of
your mind? Don't shut it yet!
[HANNES] We've still got people
out there! Give 'em a chance!
We can't let the Titans
get through the Inner Gate.
If that happens, the handful
of lives left out there'll be
the least of our problems! There
aren't enough resources for
the whole human
race to retreat behind
the next wall if
they break through!
Listen to yourself!
We're soldiers;
we don't get to decide
who lives or dies!
What are you waiting for?
The Titans are
closing the gap!
That does it, bring 'er down!
No!
Let go of me!
[gasp]
♪
[HUGO] What the hell?
[HUGO] Oh no.
Fire!
What?
Impossible!
We've gotta get
the hell out of here!
Retreat! Retreat!
Shut the gate, now!
We're being charged!
[HUGO] Go, go, go!
♪
[shaky breathing]
[HANNES] Oh, God.
[NARRATOR] Bad news
travels fast.
[NARRATOR] Hours
after Shiganshina fell,
[NARRATOR] every man, woman,
and child within the Interior
[NARRATOR] knew the unthinkable
had come to pass.
[NARRATOR] Terror
spread like wildfire.
[LORD] What do you think we're
meant to make of these reports
[LORD] of Shiganshina
falling to the Titans?
Are they verified?
That outcropping has held
for a century;
it makes no sense.
Whether or not they're verified.
The refugees are certainly
flooding in like plague rats.
There've been at least
five-hundred accounted
for in the boats.
The question is how prepared are
we if Shiganshina is in ruins?
Come now. Surely Wall Maria
is enough on its own to
hold the Titans at
bay, don't you think?
Damn it all. Any way it's sliced
the situation is untenable.
Our hands are tied.
I say we make appeals
to the Central
Government for help.
[ELITE] Excuse me, my lords!
You'll really
want to hear this!
Wall Maria's been
broken through.
The Titans are-- They're in!
This is the end.
[COMMONER] That's it.
We're all dead.
We're dead and standing
at the gate of Hell.
[EREN] It's gone.
Our house. It's
all gone. Forever.
[EREN] Forever.
[EREN] Why was I
always such a brat?
[EREN] Why did I
always fight her?
[EREN] I never said,
"I love you."
[EREN] Now I'll never get to.
[EREN] Never!
There's nothing you could've
done for her, you understand?
Because I'm a kid.
Because I'm weak.
Because every last one
of us is a damn coward!
[fighting tears]
[EREN] No. This is over.
What're you--?
[ARMIN] What's wrong?
You see something?
[ARMIN] Eren.
I'm going to
put a stop to this!
I'll kill them all.
Every last one.
Eren.
[NARRATOR] In terrified haste,
The Central Government
[NARRATOR] declared the
Outlier Districts a lost cause
[NARRATOR] and decreed
all mankind retreat
[NARRATOR] behind Wall Rose.
Estimates held that nearly
[NARRATOR] ten-thousand
lives were lost
[NARRATOR] to the
Titan offensive.
Eren. Carla. Mikasa.
Please be alive!
[GRISHA] Eren! Stay
with me, boy! Wake up!
[EREN] Stop it!
Please, you're scaring me!
[EREN] I don't understand
what you're trying to do!
[GRISHA] You don't have to!
Just give me your arm!
[EREN] No! You're insane!
[EREN] Mom's death pushed
you off the deep end!
[GRISHA] Shut up!
[EREN] Get off! Let me go!
Damn you, this
is the only way!
[EREN] You're not
making any sense!
[GRISHA] You cannot
forget the key!
[GRISHA] Whatever you
do, you must reach it!
[GRISHA] It's the
way to the Truth!
[GRISHA] One day
you'll understand!
[bells ringing]
Hey. It's okay.
You were just dreaming.
Dad was-- It felt so real.
Nightmare. Shake it off.
Yeah.
[MIKASA] Come on.
They're handing out food
rations near the warehouse.
[MIKASA] I think this
used to be where they
[MIKASA] stored
all the dry goods.
[MIKASA] Now it's where
they corral the refugees.
[gasp]
[chattering]
[COMMONER] I don't
think so, friend!
[ANOTHER COMMONER]
Give me a break!
All I've had for two
days is a moldy bit of crust!
Not exactly a
dignified existence.
[ARMIN] Hey guys!
[EREN] Armin.
Glad I caught you. Here.
Grandpa scrounged a little extra
by telling the
powers-that-be he had kids.
That was nice of him.
Tch!
What's his deal?
Just ignore it.
There's a shortage.
Poor man's probably hungry.
By the way,
I'd make that last.
[ARMIN] They were
already dealing with famine
[ARMIN] before we
got here, so it's
[ARMIN] an ugly situation.
That, and this far in
[ARMIN] there's a
greater disparity between
[ARMIN] the haves
and the have-nots.
Nothin' more gratifyin' than
seein' your rations
go to animals.
Guess we gotta beef
up the herd, though.
Eat up, the Titans like a
little meat on their bones!
Eren, wait!
Oughta keep you in cages.
Shove you out to the
frontlines as a buffer.
Oww! Damn it! You picked
the wrong man, asshole!
Spineless cowards! All of you!
You don't-- You don't
know what it's like!
Huh?
You seen one? You
seen what they can do?
You little piece o'--
He's sorry! He didn't
mean it; he's just hungry.
We all get that way; speak our
minds out of turn sometimes?
Forgive him. I beg you.
Yeah, well. Keep in
mind who's givin' up
their share so you can eat.
In case you hadn't
noticed, we're all hungry.
[ELITE] Tell your buddy a little
gratitude goes a long way.
Sure!
Bastard. I'm not about to
show gratitude to a coward!
[EREN] I can't do this.
I'm going back to Wall Maria.
[EREN] The Titans have to pay
for what they've done to us.
Hey, now. You're not serious;
that's your stomach talking.
No, it's not!
Wake up! The guys standing
between us and them
are just a bunch of talk!
To hell with all of 'em!
Here. I'm going back!
Yeah? What're you
tying to do, starve?
When are you gonna
get sick of their charity?
Too much is handed to us!
We have to stand
on our own two feet!
To do what? Get
killed by a Titan?
I know I used
to think our future
was beyond the walls. But
it's like you told that man.
I'd never seen what
they could do to us!
So that's it? This
is just the way life is?
Run away and take
what we're given?
Look at us! What
choice do we have here?
We can damn-well leave!
If you wanna scrape by on
the charity of cowards,
that's your thing,
but I'm not a parasite!
[ARMIN] Mikasa.
[MIKASA] Have you looked
in the mirror lately?
[MIKASA] All of
us are parasites.
[MIKASA] We couldn't run from
certain death without help.
[MIKASA] Tell me differently.
[MIKASA] Don't take your
shortcomings out on him.
[MIKASA] For god's sake, we
can't even find food on our own.
[MIKASA] We're parasites.
We're cowards.
[MIKASA] Titans are at the
top of the food chain. Period.
Pride be damned; we
do what we must to live.
Your mom didn't
ask us to be brave.
Mikasa!
Eat it. She asked
us to stay alive.
I'm not about to let her down.
[crying]
♪
[NARRATOR] A few days later,
throngs of starved refugees
[NARRATOR] were put to
plough in the wastelands
[NARRATOR] as a last-ditch
effort to raise food.
[NARRATOR] But the cold,
hard ground yielded nothing.
[NARRATOR] And the following
year, 846, the remaining
[NARRATOR] refugees old enough
to serve in the military
[NARRATOR] were tasked
with reclaiming Wall Maria.
[NARRATOR] Of the 250,000 sent,
[NARRATOR] nearly twenty percent
of the surviving population,
[NARRATOR] not even
two hundred made it back.
[NARRATOR] While it did nothing
to drive back the Titans,
[NARRATOR] their sacrifice
did at least lessen the effects
[NARRATOR] of famine
within the Interior.
[crying]
[EREN] We have to
find a way to stop them.
[EREN] Our lives will never
be our own until we do.
[EREN] This world
will never feel like home.
That's it. Next year I'll
be applying to join the Cadets.
To become strong
enough to fight back.
I'm with you.
You don't have to--
I do.
[MIKASA] So do I.
Damn it! I'm not
trying to drag you in.
Look, there's no point
in following me to my death!
Yeah. And if I can help it,
then it won't be your death.
All right. Together then.
[KEITH] Straighten
those spines, piss-ants!
[KEITH] The 104th Cadet
Corps Boot Camp starts now!
Allow me to introduce myself:
I'm Commandant Keith Sadies;
And you will grow to hate me.
Training is gonna be a
white-knuckle ride through Hell.
If I've done my job, you'll
be waking up in a cold sweat
[KEITH] from memories
of this place every night
[KEITH] for the rest
of your miserable lives.
[KEITH] Right now,
you're nothing. Livestock.
[KEITH] But over the next
three, soul-crushing years,
[KEITH] you'll learn to
take down your own Goliath.
[KEITH] Remember this moment
when you come face to face
[KEIHT] with him, 'cause
here's where you ask yourself:
[KEITH] Am I a fighter,
or am I feed?
[KEITH] Am I gonna be ground
up to pulpy human grist
'tween boulder-sized incisors.
[KEITH] Or am I gonna
be the one to bite?
Oh, I'm a fighter, alright.
And before I'm done with 'em,
the Titans will
grow to hate me.
[NARRATOR] It isn't easy.
[NARRATOR] Hard truth:
Passion's no guarantee you'll
[NARRATOR] stick the landing.
Unless you can transmute it
[NARRATOR] into skill. When
you're floored by fundamentals
[NARRATOR] all the heart in
the world means nothing.